我要给你们讲的这个故事
I'm going to tell you a story
里面有个永远长不大的男孩儿
about a boy who would never grow up,
一个一心要除掉他的海盗
about the pirate who wished to kill him,
还有座精灵遍布的岛屿
about the island where fairies roamed.
但跟你之前听过的版本不一样
But this isn't the story you've heard before,
因为有时朋友是不打不相识的对手
because sometimes friends begin as enemies,
有时敌人  是反目的朋友
and enemies begin as friends.
有时要想真正理解故事的结局
Sometimes to truly understand how things end,
首先得了解它的开始
we must first know how they begin.
永远谨慎的修女
朗伯斯区男孩之家
由志愿者捐赠建立
我爱你  我的孩子
I love you, my son.
我爱你  我的彼得
I love you, my Peter.
彼得潘
醒醒  都醒醒
Wakey, wakey!
太阳晒屁股了
Rise and shine!
快点  起床了
Come on, now.
这就对了  快起床
That's it. Come on.
走了走了  动作快
Move along. Come on, quickly now.
12年后  伦敦  第二次世界大战
走了走了  动作快
Move along. Come on, quickly now.
12年后  伦敦  第二次世界大战
.
彼得  我们要错过早餐了
Peter, we'll miss breakfast.
英雄归来  他们得填饱肚子
The heroes have risen. They must now feed!
那边安静点儿
Quiet over there!
我说安静
I said quiet!
马上吃了它
Eat that up! Now.
别让再我重复
I won't tell you again!
熏肉呢
Where's the bacon?
周末都有熏肉皮的
We always have bacon rind of a weekend.
正打仗呢  彼得  限量供应
There's a war on, Peter. Rationing.
你们能有东西吃就不错了
You're lucky to have any food at all.
巴拿巴院长  原谅我
Oh! Mother Barnabas, forgive me.
让开
Get over there.
你赌不赌她肯定是私吞了所有配给
How much you wanna bet she's nickin' all the rations?
嘘  小点儿声  她会听到的
Shh. She'll hear ya.
她的耳朵和大象一样
She's got ears like an elephant.
屁股也像
Bum like one, too.
你看
Look.
空座位更多了
More empty seats.
尼尔森和比利都被撤离了
Nelson and Billy both got evacuated.
幸运的家伙
Lucky sods.
两个都走了吗
Both of them?
-什么时候  -不知道
- When? - Don't know.
我醒来的时候  他们都走了
When I woke up, they were both gone.
去了加拿大的一个家庭  等战争结束
Off to some family in Canada until the war's over.
我觉得去那也挺好的
I wouldn't mind goin' there.
别傻了  你就好好待在这儿吧
Don't be daft. You gotta stay put.
等咱们妈妈来接咱们吗
For when our mums come fetch us?
没错
Exactly.
我们据守这里  保卫要塞
We hunker down here. Hold the fort.
等待骑兵部队的到来
Wait for the cavalry.
去房顶把那些肮脏的檐槽打扫干净
Now, get on that roof and clean those filthy gutters.
这安全吗  巴拿巴院长
Is it safe, Mother Barnabas?
我倒是没有亲自检查过
Well, I've not tested it meself, like.
最近没有
You know, not recently.
但是孤儿坠楼死亡需要的
But all the necessary paperwork is in order
文件手续我都一应而全
should an orphan perish in a fall.
马上给我上去
Now get up there!
等你上去了也就离上帝更进了
And while you're aloft and closer to our Lord,
或许你可以反省反省你肮脏的灵魂
you may reflect on your festering souls.
你那和枯叶一样腐败的心
Your souls that fester as do the leaves.
看吧  我就说了嘛
See! I was right!
她私藏了供给
She's hoarding all the rations.
她把那些食物都藏哪儿去了
Where's she hiding all the grub?
在她办公室  从没有人去过那儿
Her office. No one's ever been in there.
我听说  那儿还设了陷阱呢
I heard a rumor it's booby trapped.
安静  都给我安静
Silence, I said! Quiet!
所有人  都到防空洞去
Everyone, down to the shelters!
混乱里死路一条
In chaos is death!
-快来  -我觉得这样不好
- Come on. - I don't like this.
福特诺克斯
Fort Knox.
恶龙之巢穴
The lair of the dragon.
快过来
Come here.
拉住这里
So put your hands there.
你的鞋给我  伙计
I need your shoe, fella.
-你能不能  -小点儿声
- Could you just... - Quiet!
好了
Right.
Nineteen.
Twenty.
彼得
Peter.
额  这老修女真邋遢
Ugh. What a dirty old nun.
额
Ugh.
这儿也太脏了
This is so unhygienic.
但圣母玛利亚为什么却那么干净
Why is the Virgin Mary so clean?
-尼布斯  -下面
- Nibs? - Down here!
尼布斯
Nibsy!
我说了的吧
I told ya.
陷阱
Booby trapped.
宝藏哎
It's a treasure trove.
天哪
Flippin' heck!
彼得
Peter!
是档案
It's the records.
彼得
Peter!
你的资料
It's your file.
是你妈妈写的吗
Is it from your mum?
都写什么了
What does she say?
我看不懂
I can't.
你能读一下吗
Will you read it?
-不是默读  -哦
- I meant aloud. - Oh.
'我最爱的彼得"
"My dearest Peter."
"我所做的一切  都是因为我爱你"
"Everything I have done, I have done because I love you."
"我渴望哪天能回到你身边"
"I long for the day that I can come back for you"
"向你解释一切"
"And explain everything."
"不要质疑我"
"Don't doubt me"
"最重要的是  不要质疑你自己"
"Nor most importantly, don't doubt yourself."
"你是独一无二的"
"You are extraordinary."
"远超你的想象"
"More than you can imagine."
"我保证我们还会见面"
"I promise that you will see me again,"
"这个世界  或另一个世界"
"in this world or another."
那是我的私人财产  还给我
That's my private property! Give it back!
告诉你  彼得
You know, Peter,
每个孤儿都以为自己很特别
every little orphan dreams he's special.
幻想着妈妈欢呼雀跃的来找他们
That he'll be the one whose mother comes a-skipping back for him.
但是你的妈妈不会来
But your mammy's not for skipping.
为什么呢
And why is that, hmm?
因为你不够特别  彼得
Because you're not special, Peter.
就是对你自己而言
You're not even special
你都平庸无奇
in your own way.
你只是个被没有责任心  完全忘记你的存在的
You're just a nasty little creature abandoned by a feckless mammy
母亲抛弃的脏东西
who's forgotten you exist.
你个小野蛮人
Oh! You little savage!
手伸出来  两个人都罚
Hands! The both of ya!
他又没干什么
He never did nothin'!
他是从犯
He's guilty by association.
是痛苦降临的时候了
It is time for the pine.
喂  小竹竿
Oi, Skinny.
阿诺德和双胞胎
Arnold and the twins,
他们什么时候走的
when did they go?
我猜是昨晚吧
Me guess it were last night.
那些消失的孩子
All the missing children,
还有藏在她办公室的钱
all that dough hidden in her office.
巴拿巴打算干什么
What's Barnabas up to?
她在贩卖孤儿
She's selling orphans.
我就知道
I knew it!
我是说  她真的有吗  这不好哎
I mean, is she? That's not nice.
但谁会大晚上的买孤儿呢
But who in the world buys orphans at night?
这就是我们要调查的
That's what we have to find out.
快来  咱俩制定个计划  一定很有趣
Now, come on, let's make a plan. It'll be fun.
这话真耳熟
I've heard that one before.
谁放屁了
Cor! Who guffed one?
尼布斯
Nibsy!
才不是我
I never.
这计划真傻  我回去睡觉了
This was a stupid plan. I'm going back to bed.
走吧
Come on.
-晚安  -晚安
- Night. - Night.
-尼布斯  -彼得
- Nibs! - Peter!
我跟你说了今晚会发生
I told you it would happen tonight.
我是对的
I was right!
什么
What?
往楼梯跑
Head for the stairs.
跑
Go!
尼布斯
Nibs!
再见  彼得
Goodbye, Peter!
-跟我来吧  -放开我
- You're comin' with me! - Let go!
彼得
Peter.
我的老天爷啊
Holy pudding!
准备起航
Prepare to set sail!
我们必须离开这儿
We've gotta get out of here.
我们得跳下去
We'll have to jump.
我不敢
I can't!
没别的办法
We have to!
快点儿
Come on!
尼布斯
Nibs!
我们走咯
And away we go!
快点儿
Come on!
永远的朋友
Friends till death!
彼得
Peter!
注意  空军指挥部
见鬼  你把我的护卫舰弄沉了
Damnation. You've sunk my frigate.
长官  德国空军  入境了
Ma'am. Luftwaffe. Inbound.
姑娘们
Ladies.
6号区域  8号区域  12号区域
Sector 6, sector 8, sector 12.
炸弹
Incoming!
开火
Spitfire!
-离开甲板  -拿好武器
- Clear the deck! - Ready your swords!
哦  不是吧
Oh, come on!
长官  根据判断
Ma'am, regarding identification
敌机  更像是个...
of the enemy, um, aircraft, it rather resembles a, um...
赶紧说
Spit it out, man.
更像是艘海盗船  长官
It looks like a pirate ship, ma'am.
什么
Come again?
开火
Fire!
下去
Get off.
别想死
Don't go dying.
你可是贵重的货物
You're precious cargo.
-我吗  -反正有人这么认为
- Am I? - Somebody thinks so.
是我妈妈吗
Is it my mother?
要上升了
Going up!
出来  你们这些小老鼠
Get out here! You little rat!
快点儿
Make your move!
过来  快点儿
Come on, hurry up!
快快快
Move it! Come on!
-在码头把船停好  -拽过来
- Right this ship for docking. - Haul away!
走吧  伙伴们
Come on, fellas.
快看  有光线
Look! It's daylight.
我看看
I wanna see this!
-那是什么  -起开  我看不到了
- What is that? - Move, I can't see.
*你好  你好  你好  还有多远*
*Hello, hello, hello, how low?*
这是加拿大吗
Is this Canada?
*点起灯火*
*Turn the lights out*
*并不危险*
*It's less dangerous*
*我们来了*
*Here we are now*
*盛情款待*
*Entertain us*
*我觉得好傻*
*I feel stupid*
*却又不能自已*
*And contagious*
*我们来了*
*Here we are now*
*盛情款待*
*Entertain us*
*嘿*
*Hey!*
*你好  你好  你好  还有多远*
*Hello, hello, hello, how low?*
跟着唱
Sing!
*你好  你好  你好  还有多远*
*Hello, hello, hello, how low?*
跪下
Kneel!
我不会向任何人下跪
I don't kneel to anyone.
你会向他下跪的
Oh, you'll kneel to him.
他是令所有海盗恐惧的海盗之王
He's the pirate all pirates fear!
噩梦之源
The original nightmare!
人称黑胡子
The man they call Blackbeard!
*我已忘记我为什么品尝*
*And I forget just why I taste*
*想到了  是因为它让我开心*
*Oh, yeah, I guess it makes me smile*
*它可是非常  非常难找到的东西*
*I found it hard, so hard to find*
*没事儿  别介意*
*Oh, well, whatever, never mind*
*你好  你好  你好  还有多远*
*Hello, hello, hello, how low?*
*点起灯火*
*With the lights out*
*并不危险*
*It's less dangerous*
*我们来了*
*Here we are now*
*盛情款待*
*Entertain us*
*我觉得好傻  却又不能自已*
*I feel stupid and contagious*
歌颂我们伟大的主人
Sing for your master!
*我们来了*
*Here we are now*
*盛情款待*
*Entertain us*
可爱的软弱的孩子们
Sweet, gentle children.
你们落下滚烫的晶莹无辜的眼泪
You who weep molten pearls of innocent tears,
擦干它们  亲爱的
dry them, dear nippers.
我已经帮你们摆脱了人生残酷的牢笼
For I have sprung you from life's cruel dungeon,
现在我还你自由
and hereby grant you liberty!
不再受苦
Suffer no more.
到我这儿来  你们现在到家了
Come unto me. You are home.
这里有你们一样来自世界各地的孤儿
Here you join orphans alike from every corner of the globe,
不同的种族  信仰  肤色
every race, creed, and color.
不同的年龄和地区
Every age and era.
你们是先驱
You are pioneers.
一个新社会无畏的开创者
Brave creators of a new society.
正因如此  孩子们  这里才满是机遇
For this, my poppets, is a land of opportunity!
我的裁决是公正的
My justice is divine.
我的法律很简单
My laws are so simple
一只猪耳朵就能写得下
you could write them on a pig's ear.
其实  我就是写在猪耳朵上的
In fact, I have.
第一条  "机灵诚实地为我效力的人
Law number one, "Those who work with bright, honest vigor
"会得到奖品
"Will be rewarded with prizes
"战利品
"And trophies
"和甜品"
"And confectionery!"
第二条
Law number two,
"不努力干活儿的人
"Those who fail to work hard,
"偷奸耍滑的人
"Those who skive or malinger,
"将亲身体会对抗我的下场"
"Will hereby know the brooding majesty of my disapproval."
牢牢记住我说的话
Mark me well.
我不懂怜悯
I know no pity.
不给第二次机会  更不会手下留情
No second chances. I don't do mercy.
但是记住
But remember,
别忘了给你们自己
don't forget to help yourselves
找很多很多  很多乐子
to lots and lots of jolly old fun!
机灵鬼们
Hey, kiddiewinks,
欢迎来到永无岛
welcome to Neverland!
都给我努点儿力
Put some effort into it.
你最好能为我找到仙尘
You better find me some Pixum!
努力  再努力
Harder! Work harder!
山姆·斯密戈尔  管理者
Uh, Sam Smiegel, supervisor.
不用了  谢谢你  把它脱下来
No, thank you. Take it off.
-哇哦  -打扰一下
- Whoa! - Excuse me.
我们到底在挖什么
What are we digging for?
没人告诉你吗
Did no one explain?
我们在开采
We are mining
这些小家伙
for these little chaps.
精灵尘  也就是大家熟知的仙尘
Fairy dust, otherwise known as Pixum.
精灵真的存在
Fairies are real?
它们真的存在  当然
Mmm. They were real, yeah.
原先数以百万计  遍布在这岛上
There were millions of them all over the island.
他们去哪了
What happened to 'em?
黑胡子在将他们赶尽杀绝
Oh, Blackbeard hunted them into extinction.
-为什么  -为了精灵尘
- Why? - For the fairy dust.
你知道的  仙尘
You know, the old Pixum.
他要这个做什么
What does he want it for?
我也不知道
I don't have no idea.
没人知道  也没人被允许知道
No one knows. No one's allowed to know.
你最好不要纠结这个问题了
Well, you best not dwell on it. Just...
继续干活
Get a move on!
真实  存在的精灵
Real, actual fairies.
嘿  新来的
Hey, new kid,
你刚才坐着海盗船来到这儿
you just got here on a flying pirate ship.
真实  对你来说是个抽象概念
"Real" should be a very fluid concept for you right now.
赶紧挖吧
Get to diggin'.
把你的镐给我  小鬼
Give me your pick, kid.
你的手满是伤是因为你的刀刃钝了
Your hand's all messed up because your blade is blunted.
你要继续这样捣
If you keep swingin' like that,
会伤到你的手腕
you're gonna break your wrist.
我叫彼得
I'm Peter.
你来这儿多久了
How long have you been here?
永恒一样久
Forever.
你知道他们为什么那么想得到它吗
Do you know why they want it so badly?
仙尘
The Pixum?
你的问题太多了  小子
You ask too many questions, kid.
他们为它而杀戮  我们为它而牺牲
They kill for it. We die for it.
故事结束
End of story.
-非常感谢  -不用谢我
- Thanks very much. - Don't thank me.
我不关心你
I don't care about you.
我不是你朋友  也不会照顾你
I'm not your friend, and I haven't got your back.
就这么简单
Simple as that.
走开  小孩
Shoo, kid.
精灵尘
Fairy dust.
我找到一颗
I found some.
那是我的
That's mine!
不
No!
我找到一颗
I found some!
小偷  那是我找到的
Oi, thief! I found it!
小屁孩  闭嘴
Oi, small fry, button it.
躲开
Move!
给我
Give it to me.
是我找到的仙尘
It was me! I found the Fairy Pixum!
被这个混蛋抢走了
This bogey stole it.
他说是他找到的
He said he found it.
那就是他找到的  清楚不
That means he found it. Clear?
跟你那张丑脸上的伤疤一样清楚
Clear as the scar on your ugly face!
带他去见船长  扰乱秩序  出言不逊
Take him to the Captain! Disorder and verbals.
让开  让开
Move out of the way. Move it.
让开
Get out of the way!
这  这是有程序的
There... There is a procedure for this, you know.
你不该...
You're not supposed to...
-闭嘴  写字板先生  -哦
- Shut it, Mr. Clipboard. - Oh!
看黑胡子怎么处理这可恶的小贼
Let's see what Blackbeard makes of this nasty little thief.
你看什么  我已经尽力了
Oh, what you lookin' at? I was tryin' my best.
继续  回去干活  谢谢
Well, go on, then. Back to work. Thank you.
你找到土著人的营地了吗
Did you find the natives' camp?
我们暴露了  先生
They found us, sir.
他们从树林里突袭出来
They sprang from the trees
杀了40个我们最强的战士
and laid waste to 40 of our most formidable men.
然后他们钻回森林
Then they disappeared back
消失得无影无踪
into the forest as if they were never there.
我们会找到他们的  船长
We will get them, Captain.
给点时间
Given the proper time.
时间
Time?
我都把这些矿榨干了
I have sucked these mines dry.
已经所剩无几  我必须占领他们的土地
There's almost nothing left. I must have their lands.
可这些野蛮人还能不断地伏击我的船
But these savages continue to ambush my ships,
从某个没人能找到的
operating from some hidden camp,
隐蔽营地操作
which no one can seem to find.
就这样你还跟我保证
And yet you assure me
再给点时间  你就能搞定一切
all will be well given the proper time.
没时间了  没有
There is no time! None!
打扰一下  船长
Excuse me, Captain.
嘿吼
Hey ho.
表演必须继续
The show must go on.
矿工们看上去怎样
How do the miners seem?
肮脏  狂热  处在崩溃的边缘  先生
Dirty, feverish, on the brink of collapse, sir.
为什么非得这么难呢
Why must it be so hard?
那么
So...
今天我们要拿谁开刀
Who are we making an example of today?
*嘿吼  出发*
*Hey ho, let's go*
*他们排着整齐的队伍*
*They're forming in a straight line*
*他们乘着疾驰的摩托*
*They're going through a tight wind*
不  不
No, no!
这是要干吗
What's going on?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
*他们迅速跳上后座*
*They're piling in the backseat*
*他们立刻热血沸腾*
*They're generating steam heat*
*和着节拍*
*Pulsating to the backbeat*
*闪电战波普*
*The Blitzkrieg Bop*
现在清楚了吗
Any clearer now?
嘿吼  出发
Hey ho, let's go!
永无岛的勇士们
Brave heroes of Neverland,
看看这些叛徒
behold these traitors.
我把他们的命运交给你们仁慈的审判
I entrust their fate to your gracious whim.
这个野蛮人
This barbarian...
在粮店偷盗时被抓
...caught stealing from the grain store.
在粮店偷叫时被抓
...was caught squealing from the grain store.
偷盗
Stealing.
-偷盗  -两次
- Stealing. - Twice.
两次
Twice!
-你们要释放他吗  -不
- Will you spare him? - No!
还是要弘扬正义
Or do you lust for justice?
正义
Justice!
-没错  -正义
- Yes! - Justice!
-他们有发慈悲的时候吗  -有的
- Do they ever have mercy? - Oh, yes. They do.
经常吗
Often?
出发
Let's go!
别回答
Don't answer that.
这个男孩才刚到矿上一天
This boy has been in our mines but one day
就已经证明自己有贼的潜质
and has already proven himself to be a thief,
是个捣乱头子  仙尘诈骗犯
a rabble rouser, and a Pixum fraudster.
-我不是  -回答我
- I never! - I ask,
你们会对这任性的孩子心慈手软吗
shall you have mercy for the willful child?
不会
No!
还是要对他严惩不贷
Or do ye be nasty?
严惩
Nasty!
严惩  严惩  严惩
Nasty! Nasty! Nasty!
可惜
Alack.
民意不可违
The people have spoken.
想点开心事
Think a happy thought.
这是真的吗
I'll be darned.
真不敢相信  我能飞
I don't believe it! I can fly!
永无岛是个你永远醒不过来的梦
Neverland is a dream from which you never wake.
做过这样的梦吗
Ever had that one?
一个噩梦  你明知是假的
A dreadful nightmare you know is not real,
但你睡得太沉
but your sleep is so heavy,
太深  太香
so deep, so delicious
怎么也醒不过来
that you just can't wake up.
溺在了梦里
Drowning in sleep.
慢节奏的梦
Slow dream
溺亡在柔软  黑色的海洋里
drowning in the soft, black sea.
你知道那片海吗  彼得
Do you know that sea, Peter?
是死亡  孩子
It's death, boy.
对你低语
Murmuring to you.
那是我们的结局
It's where we end.
大多数人吧
Most of us.
要吃点巧克力吗
Would you like some chocolate?
童年并不愉快
Childhood ain't so jolly.
相反  很可怕
In fact, it's rather frightening.
是不是
Agree?
你勇敢吗  彼得
Are you brave, Peter?
我尽量
I try to be.
当然
Yes, of course.
你害怕吗
Are you scared?
害怕
Yes.
你以前飞过吗
Have you ever flown before?
没有
No.
那堵墙后面  有群野蛮人
Beyond that wall, there are savage people.
他们有一个古老的预言
They have an ancient prophecy
从精灵王国统治这个岛时就已存在
from when the fairy kingdoms reigned on this island.
预言说  有一个男孩
The prophecy tells of a boy born of the love
为精灵王子和人类女孩相爱所生
between a fairy prince and a human girl.
他会从这个世界消失
A boy who would be disappeared from this world
长大后再回归
until he was old enough
领导一场暴动推翻我
to return and lead an uprising against me.
预言说  这个男孩
A boy, so says the prophecy,
他会飞
who could fly.
你是来杀我的吗  彼得
Have you come to kill me, Peter?
我不相信睡前故事
I don't believe in bedtime stories.
"我...  我"
"Me... Me."
我保证你会再见到我
I promise that you will see me again,
这个世界  或另一个世界
in this world or another.
"或另一个世界"
"Or another."
走  进去
Go on! Get in there!
或另一个世界
"Or another."
-小飞孩  -怎么了
- Hey, flyboy. - Yeah?
你这场飞行表演不错啊
That was some little airshow you put on out there.
你能再飞一次吗
Could you do that again?
问话的是谁
Who wants to know?
我当然能飞  你见过的
Of course I can fly. You saw me.
很好
Good.
把你的耳朵贴到那边的墙上
Put your ear to that wall over there.
你听到的是我贴到墙外的
Now that's the sound of a blast cap
定时炸弹声
I stuck to the other side.
设置为30秒后爆炸
Set to go off in 30 seconds.
要是我能飞  你会帮我找到妈妈吗
If I fly, you'll help me find my mother?
我知道她肯定在这座岛上
I reckon she's here on the island.
这不是谈判  孩子
It's not a negotiation, kid.
没有我  你都逃不出这牢房
Without me, you're stuck in this cell.
没有我  你也逃不出这矿区
Without me, you're stuck in these mines.
好吧  我们以后讨论一下
Okay, then we'll talk about it.
现在离那堵墙远点
Just move away from that wall
不然你会被炸到
before you get yourself blown up, all right?
-那你到底答不答应  -孩子
- So, what's it gonna be? - Kid!
嘀哒
Tick
滴答
tock.
好吧  成交  只要你
Okay, we have a deal, just...
小飞孩
Flyboy?
快  滑下去  他们会来追我们的
Hurry! Slide down. They'll be comin' for us.
要让我相信你  我得先知道你的名字
If I'm gonna trust you, I need to know your name.
虎克  我叫詹姆斯·虎克
It's Hook. The name's James Hook.
-高兴了吧  -不
- Happy? - No!
左脚放在右脚前
Left foot in front of the other,
右脚放在左脚前
put the right one in front of the other.
就这样  这叫走路  走  继续
That's it. It's called walking. Off you go. Go on.
斯密
Smee.
继续  别停
Well, go on, then. Carry on.
斯密  下面
Smee. Down here!
6点钟方向
Six o'clock.
我不...  是...
I don't... Yes...
该死  斯密  篮子里
Darn it, Smee, in the basket.
请别叫我斯密
Please don't call me Smee.
斯密  能送我去楼顶吗
Smee, can you get me to the surface?
没用的
There is no use.
上去了之后  也没别的路可走了
Once you're up there, you can't get anywhere else.
今天不一样
Not today.
认识你真好
Good knowing ya.
你一直都是真朋友
You've been a true friend.
某天我会想办法报答你
Someday I'll find a way to repay you.
现在  把我们送上去吧
Now, send us up.
搞什么鬼
What the heck?
你刚才说某天你会想办法报答我
You just said someday you'll find a way to repay me.
某天  不是今天  出去
Someday, not today. Get out!
我觉得这只是个说法问题
I think that's a very minor technicality.
某天也可以是今天  你想想看
Someday could be today, if you think about it.
-再说...  -斯密
- And, moreover... - Smee!
遵命
Yes.
我们要去那里
That's where we're headed.
直升机场
The Skyport.
我们可以坐缆车到码头
We can take one of the cable cars up to the dock.
然后你可以带我们飞到船上
Then you'll fly us to a ship.
行吗
Okay?
躲好了  孩子
Keep your head down, kid.
走  走
Go! Go!
看见没  他们把帆船停得里码头很远
See? They anchor the galleons far enough off the dock,
这样就没人能偷走了
so they're impossible to steal.
你的意思是让我从码头飞到其中一个
So you want me to fly from the dock, over to one of the...
什么  赶紧说  不然就永远别说
What? Speak now, or forever hold your peace.
我们应该停下来吗
Are we meant to have stopped?
用力  用力
Heave! Heave!
到不了直升机场了  你得现在就飞
Forget the Skyport. You have to do it now.
你在等正式邀请吗
Are you waiting for a formal invitation?
-跳  赶紧  -我恐高
- Go! Now! - I'm afraid of heights!
什么  你会飞啊
What? You can fly!
昨天是我第一次飞
Yesterday was my first time.
那你最好再飞一次
Well, you better fly again,
不然我们掉下去就玩儿完了
or we're all gonna fall for the last time.
我们能以后再争论这个吗
Might we bicker about this later?
斯密  给我剑
Smee! The sword!
那能行  孩子
Yeah, that's gonna work, kid.
上去对着他们挥舞
Get up there and wave it at 'em.
用力
Heave!
好险
That was close.
你会开船吗
Do you know how to work a ship?
那能有多难
How hard could it be?
-斯密  缆绳  -是  是
- Smee! The rope! - Yes! Yes!
-好了  -孩子
- Clear! - Boy!
开船比想象得难多了
This is a lot harder than it looks!
我们扬帆起航了
Yeah! We're sailin' now!
你有什么要说的吗
Well, do you have anything to say?
我花大功夫摆好的桌子
I worked really hard setting up that table.
什么  别管桌子了  以后再捡
What? Forget the table. Pick them up later.
要是男孩找到了土著人
If that boy makes it to the natives,
我们就没机会打赢这场仗了
you can forget any chance of us winning this war.
我们会失去一切
All will be lost.
我们会找到他们  他们走不远的
We'll find them, sir. They can't have gone far.
那你说他们在哪里
Well, then where are they?
抓住那个男孩  别让他落到野蛮人手里
Get me that boy before the savages do!
正前方
Dead ahead!
斯密  放开我的腿
Smee! Get off my leg!
我觉得我要吐了
I think I'm gonna be sick!
墙  墙
The wall! The wall!
有人吗  救命啊
Somebody, please help me!
转向
Turn!
斯密  把帆撑起来
Smee! Get the sails up!
我们需要有强逆风才能开跳
We need a strong headwind to make the jump!
跳哪里
What jump?
回家  我们要离开这座该死的岛
Home! We're gettin' the heck off this island!
不
No-ho!
你说过我们要找我妈妈
You said we'd find my mother!
我不会离开永无岛的
I'm not leaving Neverland!
好吧  反正现在也走不了了
Well, not now, anyway!
把帆撑起来
Get the sails up!
帆
The sails!
这会有些颠簸
This is gonna be a little rough!
把帆撑起来
Put the sails up!
说了多少次
How many times...
我在返老还童的时候不要打扰我
I am not to be disturbed when I'm at the Rejuvenator!
什么事
Yes?
抱歉  船长  是那个男孩的事
I am sorry, Captain, but it's about the boy.
说
Mmm-hmm?
偷走的船掉进了Neverwood
The stolen ship went down in the Neverwood.
男孩丢了吗
So the boy is lost?
是的  男孩丢了
Yes, sir. He is a lost boy.
不过现在我们最优秀的战士在找他
But our best men are searching for him now.
你们这些蠢货
I am surrounded by imbeciles.
什么事都要我亲自动手吗
Must I do everything myself?
先生  您不能真的相信
Sir, you can't really believe
这个小孩就是预言中说的人
that this pipsqueak is the one.
他看上去没什么能耐
He hardly seems capable.
他妈妈看上去也没什么能耐
His mother hardly seemed capable either,
可把我们害惨了
and yet, here we are.
你答应过要帮我找到我妈妈的
The deal was to help me find my mother.
你差点就毁约  那真的很不好
You were gonna break it. That's very wrong.
不  是你先毁约的  你骗了我们
No, you broke the deal first. You lied to us.
没  我只是撒了个小谎
No, I fibbed.
我能飞  只不过不是每天而已
I can fly. Just not every day.
这艘船是我们离开这座岛的唯一希望
Our only way off this island
现在它粉身碎骨了  你满意了吧
and now it's in pieces. Satisfied?
是的  我非常满意
Well, yes. I'm quite content.
因为我不想离开这座岛
'Cause I don't wanna get off this island.
花这么多年做逃跑计划
All the years that I've wasted planning to get out.
全都泡汤了
All gone.
别翻了  这里不安全
Hey! Quit messing around. It's not safe in here.
每艘船上都有一张
Every ship has one.
一张什么
A what?
地图
A map.
这是什么意思
What does that say?
部落领土
"Tribal Territory."
没错
Exactly.
预言说  一个男孩会领导部落
The prophecy said, "A boy would lead the tribe."
那又怎样  你根本不关心
So what? You don't care.
我关心  继续说
I do. Keep going.
黑胡子认为预言是在说我
Well, Blackbeard thinks the prophecy is about me,
意味着我妈妈来自这里
which means my mum is from here,
意味着土著人可能知道她在哪里
which means the natives might know where she is.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
那些野蛮人会直接杀了你
Those savages would just as soon kill you as help you.
-你见过他们吗  -没见过
- Ever met one? - No!
我也无此打算
And I don't plan to.
他们或许很友善呢  我不怕
Well, they might be very nice. I'm not afraid of 'em.
勇敢和自杀只在一念间  小子
There's a fine line between bravery and suicide, kid.
我要去找部落领土了  再见
I'm off to go find the Tribal Territory. Oh, goodbye!
他在森林里活不到一个小时
He won't last an hour out there.
那是他的问题  不是我们的
His problem. Not ours.
问题是  如果他真是命中注定的那个
Thing is, if he was the chosen one...
就算预言是真的  相信我  那也不是他
If that prophecy is real, trust me, he ain't it.
但如果他们以为他是的话
But if they thought he was...
他们相信他是的话
They believed he was...
我肯定他们会丰厚奖赏
I bet they'd handsomely reward anyone
把他带去给他们的人
who brought him to them.
他们没有船
Well, they haven't got a ship.
是  但他们可以弄到
Yeah, but they could get one.
谁打海盗的次数多得过原住民
Who's fought the pirates more than the natives?
如果有人能办到  那一定是他们了
If anyone could find a way, it's them.
记住了  我们找到那些
Just remember, when we find those
所谓友好的原住民以后
oh-so-sweet-natured locals,
不管是真是假  你都得说你是他们的救世主
true or not, you tell them you're their savior.
然后咱们就分道扬镳  明白了吗
Then, we'll go our separate ways. Got it?
你为什么想要离开这么好的地方
Why would you want to leave a place like this?
你要去哪
Where will you go?
我不知道  不过首先肯定是个
I don't know. Somewhere I'm a little higher up
我在食物链上方的地方
on the food chain, for starters.
那是什么
What was that?
食物链上方的东西
Somethin' a little higher up on the food chain.
好美啊  虎克  你看到了吗
Oh, that is pretty, Hook. Do you see that?
我们差点被海盗用大炮打下来
We got pirates tryin' to shoot us down with cannons.
从上千尺高空掉落差点摔死
Nearly falling a thousand feet to our deaths.
而且是两次  船也毁了
Twice. Shipwrecked.
可你看到这样的景色  你就会想
And you see something like that and you think to yourself,
"太值了"
"Oh, worth it."
你是个孤儿吗
Are you an orphan?
我妈把我抛弃了  这算吗
My ma left me. That count?
你记得她吗
Well, do you remember her?
我才不要浪费眼泪去想念一个
I'm not wasting tears missing someone
从不想念我的人
who never missed me.
也许她也想你呢
Maybe she does.
你怎么知道
How can you know?
你真相信你母亲在这里吗
Do you really believe your mum's here?
她给我留了封信  上面说
Well, she left me a note saying...
是啊  她给你留了封信
Oh, well, if she left you a note, sure.
就因为你妈不爱你
Just 'cause yours never loved you...
住口
Stop.
不代表我妈从没爱过我
...doesn't mean my mum never loved me.
给我闭嘴
Stop talking right now.
你听见了吗
Did you hear that?
那噩梦一般的吼叫震耳欲聋
It was a deafening nightmare shriek.
怎么会有人听不见
How can anyone not have heard...
那是只永无鸟
That's a Neverbird.
那只也是
And so is that.
我们怎么办
What're we gonna do?
我们得想个办法  我们得想个办法
We need a plan. We need a plan!
跑
Run!
跑到雾里就能甩掉他们  快跑
We'll lose them in the mist! Go!
快跑
Go!
快跑  斯密
Run, Smee!
它们的脸很丑  但羽毛好漂亮
Their faces are terrible, but their feathers are quite lovely.
闭嘴快点跑
Shut up and run!
快跑
Go!
斯密
Smee!
彼得
Peter!
虎克  是你吗
Hook? Is that you?
彼得
Peter.
虎克  它们抓走了斯密
Hook, they've got Smee.
不
No.
别担心  一切都会没事的
Don't worry. Everything's gonna be all right!
我就知道我们会找到原住民的
I knew we'd find the natives.
我们得救了
We're saved.
求求你了  我想回家了  求求你了
Please! I'm ready to go home now, please.
让我来
Let me handle this.
美丽的姑娘  我们别无恶意
Good fair lady. We come in peace.
我们还带来了宝贝
And with treasure.
请允许我自豪地为你介绍
May I proudly present to you...
潘
Pan!
潘  潘
Pan! Pan!
潘
Pan!
潘  潘
Pan! Pan!
潘
Pan!
斯密
Smee!
-斯密  -干吗
- Smee! - What?
他们在唱什么
What are they singing about?
我不知道
Search me!
潘  潘
Pan! Pan!
你们在干什么  "潘"是什么
What's going on? What's "Pan"?
潘是我们部落最勇敢的武士
The Pan is our tribe's bravest warrior.
我们的传统是在我们杀了你和你的朋友前
It's our tradition to grant you the chance to win
会给你们个赢得自由的机会
your freedom before we kill you and your friends.
杀了我们  你要杀掉我们
Kill? What do you mean, "kill"?
你们是我们不共戴天的敌人  你们是海盗
You are our sworn enemy. You're pirates.
海盗  我们不是海盗  等等
Pirates? We're not pirates. Hold on!
那孩子是你们一直在等待的人
The kid is the one you've been waiting for.
听我说
Listen!
你们活命的机会是
Your chance to live,
派你们中最善战的人与我们的潘对战
your fiercest fighter against ours. Our Pan.
你们赢了  就能活
You win, you live.
-输了  -我已经懂了
- You lose... - I get the idea.
再见了
Bye for now.
潘
Pan!
我们怎么知道什么时候开始
So how do we know when to start?
-斯密  -干吗
- Smee! - What?
我们得跟他们说我妈的事
We have to tell them about my mother.
现在没人在乎你那该死老妈的事
No one cares about your darn mother!
抱歉  说话有点重了
Sorry, that was a bit harsh.
好吧
Okay.
公主殿下
Your Highness.
正想单独跟你聊两句呢
I was hoping to get you alone.
住手
Stop!
那个小家伙
The little one.
他戴着潘
He wears the Pan.
他是那个会飞的孩子
He's a boy that can fly.
我见过  棒极了
I've seen it. It's terrific.
我们称它为记忆树
We call this the Memory Tree.
那是战争的年代
It was a time of war.
黑胡子为了得到仙尘而摧毁了一切
Blackbeard destroyed everything in pursuit of the Pixum.
之后首领和伟大的精灵王达成协议
But then, the chief made a pact with the great fairy king,
要团结一致对付海盗
uniting our peoples against the pirates.
一天晚上  精灵王的儿子  精灵王子
One night, the king's son, the fairy prince,
溜到了黑胡子的船上
found his way onto Blackbeard's ship.
她叫玛丽  是黑胡子一生挚爱
Her name was Mary, the love of Blackbeard's life
也是他最珍视的所有物
and his most prized possession.
王子每晚都去看望玛丽
Night after night, the prince visited Mary.
当黑胡子发现后
But when Blackbeard discovered them,
他因嫉妒而恼羞成怒
he flew into a jealous rage.
为了救她  王子化为人形
So in order to save her, the prince took human form.
虽然精灵有千年寿命
But though fairies can live many thousands of years,
但化为人形后  他们只能活一天
in human flesh, they can live only one day.
王子为救心爱的姑而献出了生命
The prince sacrificed his life for the girl he loved.
而那爱情的结晶便是你
And the child of that love was you.
我们帮你母亲把你藏在了另一个世界
Our people helped your mother hide you in the other world.
他们给你做了这个图腾
And they made you this totem,
这样当你回来时  我们便能认出你
so that when you returned, we would know it was you.
我母亲后来怎么样了
What happened to my mother?
她回到了Neverwood
She returned to the Neverwood
为我们征战多年
and fought for us many years.
然后呢
And?
海盗节节胜利
The pirates were winning the war,
精灵们必须隐居起来
and the fairies had to retreat to a hidden kingdom.
他们一直留在那  隐藏着
They've remained there, in hiding,
不为黑胡子所知
unknown by Blackbeard until
直到有一天他们可以重返战场
a time when they can reemerge and fight.
我母亲呢
And my mother?
-她跟他们在一起  -她还活着
- She's with them. - She's alive?
你确定吗  我要去找她
Are you sure? I have to go to her!
-求求你  现在就带我去  -不行
- Please, take me now! - No.
你必须耐心
You must be patient.
但她在等我
But she's waiting for me.
精灵王国是这片土地上最大的秘密
The fairy kingdom is the greatest secret of this land.
我们的责任是守护这个秘密
Our duty is to protect it.
在我们带你去之前
Before we take you there,
你必须证明你就是玛丽的儿子
you must prove yourself to be Mary's son.
就是我们一直在等待的人
The one we've been waiting for.
第三天晚上的月亮升起时
When the third moon rises,
他必须飞
he must fly.
如果他活下来  他就是救世主
If he lives, he's the one.
等一下
One second.
要是他死了呢
And if he dies?
那他就是冒牌货
He's an imposter.
他是死有余辜
His death will be justified.
三天
Three days!
我有项链  这还不够吗
I've got the necklace. Isn't that enough?
有可能是你偷来的
You could've stolen it.
但我没有  你告诉她啊
But I didn't. Tell her!
这孩子一直戴着那东西
Kid's always had that thing.
你们认识他多久
How long have you known him?
-三天  -一辈子
- Three days. - All my life.
会飞的事只是个愚蠢的细节
The flying thing is a stupid detail.
他们怎么就不明白呢
Why can't they just see that?
如果你自己都不相信  彼得  那他们也不会相信
If you don't believe, Peter, then neither will they.
但如果你信  他们也会信的  我保证
But if you do, they will, too. I promise.
你是他们认为的那个人吗
Are you who they think you are?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们认为你是他们的救世主
They think you're their messiah,
你是来解放他们的
that you're here to liberate them.
他们以为的对吗
Are they right?
我说  我不知道
I said, I don't know!
兔子
Rabbits.
我相信
I believe.
我会飞
I can fly!
要是尼布斯在就好了
If only Nibs was here.
他会知道该怎么帮我
He'd know how to help.
我相信
I believe.
你见到了斯密吗
Have you seen Smee?
他们想让我做的事
These things they expect me to do,
我做不到  虎克  我试过了
I can't do them, Hook. I've tried.
-站住  -我做不到那些事
- Hey. Stop. Hey! - I can't do the things,
所以我不可能是救世主
so I can't be the one!
听着
Listen.
虎克  我到底是谁
Hook, what the bloody hell am I?
你想自怨自艾的话随你的便  小子
You can go feeling sorry for yourself all you want, kid.
但是知道你是从哪来的
But knowing where you're from,
这已经是了解你身世的一半了
that's half of knowing who you are.
已经比我们大多数人一辈子知道的都多了
That's more than most of us here will ever know.
可你说你母亲抛弃了你
But you said that your mother left you.
我骗你的  有时候我会撒谎
Yeah. I lied. I do that sometimes.
这就是成年人的世界
It's called being a grown-up!
至少你知道你是从哪来的
Least you know where you come from.
生来就是武士  王子的后裔
Born to a warrior, heir to a prince.
这意味着你就是救世主吗  我不知道
Does that mean you're the one? I don't know.
我不知道世界上到底有没有救世主
I don't know if there is a "One."
但我知道
But I do know
就算你不是那个人
that if you aren't the guy,
你只是你自己
and you are just you,
也许这就够了
maybe that's enough.
那孩子在哪
Where's the boy?
快说  不然我就杀了你
Spill the beans, or I'll spill your blood.
我绝不会说的
I'll never tell.
他就在那边
He's right over there.
不  不  稍等  我搞错了
Nope, nope. Wait, my mistake.
应该是那边  不
Pretty sure it's that way. No!
不  先转右
No. Right the first time.
绝对  也许绝对  是这边
Definitely, maybe definitely, this way.
我要说的就是  我们离得很近
The point is, we're very close.
把船准备好  象大副  杀了他
Ready the ships. Bishop, kill him.
不  等一下
No! Just wait!
等一下
Wait!
你也许现在还不想杀我
You might not wanna kill me just yet.
因为我有王冠上耀眼的明珠
For I hold the crown jewels, you know.
-比喻信息  -说
- Informationally. - Speak.
抱歉  有点紧张  你真的很吓人
Sorry, a bit nervous. You are quite intimidating.
说
Speak.
你知道所谓的灭绝了的精灵王国吧
Now, you know the so-called extinct fairy kingdom, hmm?
说
Speak.
抱歉
Sorry.
我只是在找你
I was just lookin' for you.
你找到我了
Well, you found me.
在矿里可没有这样的风景
Don't see things like that in the mines.
很美
Kinda beautiful.
你喜欢日出吗
So, do you like sunrises?
你这是在干吗
What is it you think you're doing?
我想我应该是在调情
Well, I think it's called flirting,
但如果你还得问  那我可能没做对
but if you have to ask, I might be doin' it wrong.
你不像我部落里的男人
You're not like the men from my tribe.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you.
不  他们很诚实
No, they're honesst.
-强壮  勇敢  -勇敢
- Strong. Brave. - Brave.
你管这叫勇敢吗
That what you call it?
让我的小哥们一跃而死
Letting my little buddy take a leap to his death.
当他停止怀疑自己  他会飞起来的
When he ceases to doubt himself, he will fly.
我们怎么知道这个岛上仍有精灵存在
How do we know there are any fairies still left on this island
又或者只因他们见到他飞就会来帮战
or that they'll come help fight just 'cause they see him fly?
你必须信任我们
You have to trust us.
为什么  你们显然不信任我们
Why should we? You certainly don't trust us.
精灵王国的所在地绘在一副地图中
There's a map to the fairy kingdom.
我们用自己的生命捍卫它
We guard it with our lives.
当然有地图啦
Of course there is.
秘密王国怎么会没有一张秘密地图呢
Why wouldn't there be a secret map to the secret kingdom?
这不是游戏
This isn't a game.
你已看到黑胡子对永无岛
You've seen what Blackbeard has done
做的一切了
to Neverland already.
如果我们不阻止他
He'll reduce the rest of it
他会把剩余的地方都变成矿井
to nothing but mine pits if we don't stop him.
有人告诉过你  你的眼睛很美吗
Has anybody ever told you you have really beautiful eyes?
前甲板着火  准备绕行
Fire on the foredeck, prepare to come around.
泰格·莉莉
Tiger Lily!
你打偏了
You missed.
我们必须找到彼得
We must find Peter!
打死她
Shoot her!
-彼得  -虎克呢
- Peter! - Where's Hook?
这一切都是因为你
All of this because of you.
不  夸胡  等等
No, Kwahu, wait!
不用谢  快走吧
You're welcome. Now, come on.
快跑
Keep moving!
我猜你就是公主吧
The princess, I presume.
实际上  我只是个矿工
Oh, well, actually, I'm just a miner,
不过谢谢你的赞扬
but I appreciate the compliment.
象大副
Bishop.
快走
Go on.
把他们排成一排
Line them up.
从这下去
Down here.
我们这么多年来挖断了手
All these years digging our hands raw
也只找到小块的仙尘
for tiny lumps of Pixum,
现在我从斯密先生那里得知
and now I learn from Mr. Smee
你们知道哪里有整山的仙尘
you know where there's a mountain of the stuff.
棒极了
Nice as pie.
告诉我那男孩在哪
Tell me where the boy is and
怎么找到精灵王国  你就可以活命
how to find the fairy kingdom, and you may live.
死亡是最伟大的旅程
Death is the greatest adventure.
那么旅途愉快
Bon voyage.
为我们的新女首领欢呼
All hail the new Chiefette.
泰格·莉莉公主
Princess Tiger Lily.
万岁
All hail!
告诉他吧  不然他会杀了你
Tell him. He'll kill you.
他说的没错
He's right, you know.
乖鸟
Nice birdie.
-有张地图  -叛徒
- There's a map. - Traitor.
别杀她
Don't shoot her.
她跟我说精灵王国有张地图
She told me there's a map to the fairy kingdom.
叛徒  你怎么敢背叛我们  海盗
Traitor! How dare you betray us, pirate?
我是在救你的命  亲爱的
I'm trying to save your lives, sweetheart.
不会有下次了
It won't happen again.
是不会了  我可以保证
Oh, it won't, I guarantee it.
船长
Captain.
上啊  小子
Go, kid.
杀掉他们
Kill them all!
进攻  进攻
Attack. Attack!
不
No!
我告诉你件事吧  彼得
Can I tell you something, Peter?
你永远找不到你母亲
You'll never find your mother.
不  我一定会找到她
Yes, I will find her.
不  你真真找不到
No, you really, really won't.
你永远找不到  知道为什么吗
You'll never find your mother. Do you know why?
因为我杀了她
Because I killed her.
她死在我手里  死在这把剑下
She died at my hand. By this very blade.
和你的下场一样
As you will, too.
闭上眼睛  彼得  想想开心的事
Close your eyes, Peter, and think a happy thought.
太失礼了  阁下
Bad form, sir!
我们必须逃走  马上
We have to run, now!
不  我们得跳下去
No. We have to jump.
彼得  你受伤了吗
Peter, are you hurt?
我也没事  谢谢关心
Well, I'm fine, too. Thanks for asking.
别跟我说话
Don't speak to me.
是你害得我们
Because of you, everything
竭力保护的一切面临毁灭
my people have fought to protect  will be destroyed.
是你害得首领丢掉性命
Because of you, the Chief is dead.
-斯密才是叛徒  -他是你的朋友
- Smee was the rat. - He was your friend.
-我怎么可能知道  -你应该知道
- How was I supposed to know? - You should've known.
-对不起  -你应该知道
- I'm sorry. - You should've known.
如果是我错了  我道歉
I'm sorry if I did something wrong!
彼得在哪里
Where's Peter?
彼得
Peter.
你说谎
You lied.
-你们全说谎  -对不起
- You all lied. - I'm sorry.
所以这是真的吗
So, it's true?
一言难尽
It's complicated.
我母亲是生是死
Is my mother alive or isn't she?
黑胡子的话是真的
Blackbeard spoke the truth.
而你却骗了我
And you lied to me.
如果我们告诉你她死了
Had we told you she was dead,
你会放弃你的使命
you'd have walked away from your destiny.
不管你认为我是谁
Whoever it is you think I am,
或希望我是谁
whatever it is you expect me to be,
我都不是那个人
I'm not.
我也做不到
And I can't.
我不能...
I couldn't...
我不想看着你死
I didn't wanna watch you die.
那你应该闭上眼睛
You should've closed your eyes.
黑胡子一定还在搜查彼得的下落
Blackbeard won't stop searching for Peter.
这座岛上只有一个地方他不敢去
There's only one place on this island he wouldn't dare look.
人鱼湖  听起来不错
Mermaid Lagoon? Sounds pretty.
原来海盗怕美人鱼
So pirates are afraid of mermaids?
不  是怕徘徊在湖外的东西
Because of what we will pass through to get there.
鳄鱼
Crocodiles.
害怕了
Afraid?
没有  女士
No, ma'am.
快找地图  继续找
Find the map. Keep looking.
斯密让您满意吗
Does Smee please thee?
把这里翻个底朝天
Pull the place apart!
-斯密能否重获自由  -不  你太有用了
- So may Smee be free? - No, you're too useful.
但是斯密得到承诺...
But Smee was promised...
斯密应该停止以第三人称形容自己
Smee should cease to talk of himself in the third person,
-否则斯密会有麻烦  -是
- or Smee will be a non-person. - Yes.
我找到了
I found it.
这是一幅通往精灵王国的地图
It's a map to the fairy kingdom.
准备起航
Ready the ships!
我们必须比彼得先到
We must get there before Peter.
拿火把  它们怕光
Grab the torches. They're afraid of the light.
它们被吓跑了吗
Did we scare 'em off?
拜托  它们也会飞了
Oh, come on. They can fly?
继续挥动火把
Keep waving the torches.
那里
There!
彼得
Peter!
我好像看到他了
I think I see him.
在哪
Where?
-抓住我的手  -救命  救命
- Reach for my hand! - Help! Help!
彼得
Peter.
怎么回事
What happened?
那是什么
What the heck are those?
不知道  但我觉得你应该会喜欢
I don't know, but I think you're gonna like 'em.
你说得对极了
You could say that again.
别走
Don't go.
-我去看看  -小心
- I'm gonna check it out. - Be careful.
谁还能比我更小心
Who's more careful than me?
对不起  我没有告诉你真相
I'm sorry I didn't tell you what happened to your mother.
但黑胡子的话也并非全是真的
But Blackbeard didn't tell you the whole truth either.
让我给你看
Let me show you.
美人鱼对这片水域施了记忆魔法
The mermaids charged these waters with memories.
你可以看到过去
You can see the past.
深呼吸
Deep breath.
没时间了
There's no time.
黑胡子的人快赶上来了
Blackbeard's men nearly have us.
去精灵王国
Go to the fairy kingdom.
躲起来  保护子民的安全
Hide. Keep our people safe.
你不该回来的  玛丽
You should never have come back, Mary.
然而你还是回来了
And yet, here you are.
宁愿和他们一起死也不愿与我一起活着
Ready to die for them rather than live with me.
不  玛丽
No. Mary.
不
No! No.
No!
她是位勇士
She was a warrior.
一位伟大的勇士
A great warrior.
她的牺牲至今鼓舞着我们
Her sacrifice still inspires us.
你认识她吗
Did you know her?
她是我师父
She trained me.
她会为我自豪吗
Would she have been proud of me?
会
Yes.
非常自豪
Very.
可如果我无法像她那样呢
But what if I can't do what she did?
如果我无法完成预言呢
What if I fail to fulfill the prophecy?
如果你就不去尝试呢  彼得
And what if you fail to try, Peter?
那你又算什么样的人
What are you then?
你们快来看
You've gotta see this.
船体稍微有些损坏
Now, the hull's a little banged up.
看到那些牙印了吗  那些鳄鱼跳得真高
And see those teeth marks? Boy, those crocs can jump.
待我修理一番  它就能继续航行
But once I get her fixed up, she's gonna be in good shape.
去哪
For what?
赶紧离开这座岛
To get us the hell off this island.
你打算像懦夫一样逃跑
You're going to run like a coward?
我并没有想到这个词
Well, I never really thought of it in those exact terms,
不过就是这个意思
but, generally speaking, yes.
你要逃去哪里
And where will you go?
回家
Home.
从哪来回哪去
It's, you know, where I come from.
家不是你来自哪里就是哪里  你选的才是
Home's not where you come from. It's where you make it.
那你帮我成家
So help me do that.
在黑胡子进攻下的生还者也都在矿里了
Anyone that survived Blackbeard's attack is in the mine by now.
我去过那里  我再也不会回去
And I've been there, and I'm not going back.
不管为了谁或为了什么
Not for anything or anyone.
如果你没有留下的理由那就离开
Well, if you have no reason to stay, then go.
快走  让我们等死
Go now. Leave us to die.
我不想让你死
I don't want you to die.
我想让你和我一起走
I want you to come with me.
如果我不呢
And if I don't?
那是你的决定  我无权干涉
Then that's your decision. Not mine.
孩子
Well, kid.
看来又是我们两个人一队了
Looks like the old gang's back together.
我们让船飞起来
Let's get this ship in the air.
事先声明一点
Let's get one thing straight.
我不是救世主
I'm not the chosen one,
即使预言是真的  它指的也不是我
and the prophecy wasn't about me if it was ever real at all.
但我是我母亲的儿子
But I am my mother's son.
如果黑胡子
And if Blackbeard is going
要毁掉我父母用牺牲所换来的一切
to destroy everything my parents died for,
那么我会像我父母一样和他抗争到底
I'll stand against him to the last. Just like they did.
带我去精灵王国
Now, take me to the fairy kingdom.
跟首领说的一模一样
It's just as the Chief described it.
这些是文字
These are words.
-是什么语言  -一定是精灵语
- What language is it? - Must be fairy.
我看得懂
I can read.
I can read it.
上面写了什么
What does it say?
"此门为持钥匙之王子开启"
"Only the prince who bears the key shall pass."
就这样
Just that.
还写了些关于伟人死掉的无聊故事
Then some boring stuff about the great fallen dead.
这说明我们需要钥匙
It means we need a key.
所以我们白跑了一趟
Then this was all for nothing.
我不这么认为
No, I wouldn't say that.
"持钥匙之王子"
"The prince who bears the key."
你还不懂吗  彼得
Don't you see, Peter?
-我是...  -你有钥匙
- I am the... - You bear the key.
我有吗
I do?
一直都在你身上
You've had it all along.
-她知道我会来找她  -没错
- She knew I'd come for her. - Yes.
为了保护王国  母亲将钥匙传给儿子
Mum tries to protect the kingdom by giving son the key.
我杀了母亲  却没能杀死儿子
I kill Mum, but fail to kill the son.
儿子将钥匙给了我  无法保护王国
In turn, son fails to protect the kingdom by giving me the key.
妈妈会很失望
Mum would be very disappointed.
对吧
Wouldn't she?
永恒在召唤
Eternity beckons.
我将长生不老
I will live forever.
快醒醒  太阳晒屁股啦
Wakey, wakey! Rise and shine!
那就是我们要去的地方
That's where we're going.
精灵巢穴
The fairy hive.
毁掉那里  他们就全完了
Destroy that, and we destroy them all.
太好了  太棒了
Yes! Oh! Come!
快  快来
Come on. Come.
她叫小叮当
Her name's Tinkerbell.
我听得到她说话
I can hear her.
他们一直在等你  彼得
They've been waiting for you, Peter.
你们得赶紧逃出去
You have to get away from here!
他要杀掉你们
He's going to destroy you all.
我知道我该做什么  可我失败了
I know what I was meant to do, but I failed.
对不起
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
伙计们  快烧死他们
All right, boys, let's burn them!
烧死他们
Burn them!
烧  烧  烧
Burn them, burn them, burn them!
-把他们全烧了  -不
- Burn them all! - No!
求求你  让我做什么都行
Please, I'll do anything!
-求求你  -别求饶
- Please! - Oh, don't beg.
什么都行
Anything.
求饶太丢人了
No. It's bad form to beg.
孩子  你的尊严在哪里
Where's your sense of honor, boy?
跪下
Now, kneel.
我叫你跪下
I said kneel!
我是王子和战士的儿子
I am the son of a warrior and a prince.
我永远不会对你下跪
I will never bow to you.
如果你要杀我  那就动手吧
If you're gonna kill me, then get on with it.
如你所愿
As you wish.
你不需要这样
You don't have to do this.
没错
No.
但我很想这么做
But I really want to.
想我了吗
Did you miss me?
怎么老是他
Why is it always him?
跳
Jump!
你回来了  我以为你不在乎的
You came back! I thought you didn't care!
我说过  有时候我会说谎
Like I said, sometimes I lie.
快
Come on!
我不能让黑胡子进入巢穴
I can't let Blackbeard get to the hive!
左满舵
Hard to port!
不介意我加入吧
Mind if I cut in?
我们得帮她
We've gotta help her!
你来掌舵
Take the wheel!
尽量让船靠近他们
You're gonna get this puppy as close to them as you can.
-好  -然后我跳过去
- Okay! - And I'll jump across!
抓稳了
Hold on!
船长
Captain!
不
No.
彼得  不要
Peter, no!
不
No.
一切都结束了  孩子
It's over, boy.
过来
Come.
你们  快抓住那女孩
You! Grab that girl!
潘
Pan!
我会飞了
I can fly!
快看  虎克  我在飞
Look at me, Hook, I'm flying!
好了  你有必要炫耀吗
All right, you don't have to crow about it.
随你怎么炫耀  只要别把我掉下去了
Crow all you want! Just don't drop me!
去吧
Go on.
如果要打败他  那么我们得一起上
If we're gonna beat him, we're gonna do it together.
听见了吗
Do you hear me?
很好
Good!
准备冲啊
Now, come on, then.
开火
Fire!
准备好了吗
Ready?
冲啊
Go!
抓住你了
Got you!
想想开心的事
Think a happy thought.
不
No!
孩子
Boy!
你好
Hello.
彼得
Peter.
母亲
Mum?
你找到了我
You found me.
我的眼睛和你一样
I have your eyes.
你的心和我一样
You have my heart.
这是我梦寐以求的时刻  现在...
I've imagined this moment my whole life, and now...
我爱你  母亲  十分爱你
I love you, Mum. So much.
我不懂为什么会想念一个素未谋面的人
I don't know how you can miss someone you've never met,
但我每天都在想你
but I've missed you every day.
每天
Every day?
没有你  我会再次迷失自我
Without you, I'm lost again.
我现在要怎么做
What do I do now?
你没有迷失
You're not lost.
你找到了家
You are home.
在这座岛上  和这些人
On this island, with these people.
你的子民
Your people.
你的家人
Your family.
永远不要放弃他们  正如你不曾放弃过我
You must never give up on them, as you never gave up on me.
但是  母亲
But, Mum,
我不想再次失去你
I don't want to lose you again.
你永远不会失去我
You'll never lose me.
我永远都是永无岛的一部分
I'll always be part of this Neverland.
也是你的一部分
And a part of you.
我爱你  儿子
I love you, my son.
我的彼得
My Peter.
我的彼得·潘
My Peter Pan.
彼得
Peter.
Peter?
你以为我会丢下你吗
You thought I'd leave you here.
-我从未这么想  -想开心一下吗
- No, I never. - Feel like some fun?
好啊
Yes, please.
好的  先生们
All right, gentlemen.
-抓稳了  -彼得
- Hold on tight. - Peter!
你没有绳子
You don't have a rope.
我有好多话要和你说
We have a lot to talk about.
我以为你要离开
I thought you were leaving.
改变主意了
Change of heart.
麻烦你掌舵  谢谢
Will you take the wheel, please?
你不想回家吗
You don't want to go home?
我已经到家了
I already am.
他也是海盗吗
Is he a pirate, too?
不
No.
至少还不是
Not yet, anyway.
我们要去哪里
Which way shall we go?
-设定航线  -设定航线
- Set a course! - Set a course!
谁才是老大
Hey, who's in charge here?
我是船长
Well, I'm the captain.
而我是救世主
And I'm the chosen one.
我们有的是时间去争论  小飞侠
We'll have plenty of time to argue about that later, flyboy.
随便你  虎克船长
Suit yourself, Captain Hook.
设定航线
Set a course.
驶向右边第二颗星星  一直到天明
Second to the right and straight on till morning.
永无岛
Neverland!
我们永远是朋友  对吧  虎克
We'll always be friends, Hook. Won't we?
当然  我们怎么会吵架呢
Always. What could possibly go wrong?